Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number four complexity.
Find the time complexity of this method called Hello.
It's void, it's not turning anything and took into array.
As bird meat and do some stuff.
Post the video.
Think about that right down in your paper and let us find out in the next five seconds.
Well, my friends, again, I hope you try it because writing down and trying to solve exercises is
very important.
We see here.
That.
And some equal to zero.
We start by this, we are just declaring a variable.
So all of one.
And the product also would result in all of one, OK?
Now we have done this and done this.
We entered the loop, so four and equal to zero I less than a red dot length.
I +, +, + do this stuff, this stuff is equal to zero of one, but when founding an array, it is
oh of an and all of array length.
All of our day length.
OK, so it's very important to understand that when you have an array, we are searching and doing this
stuff, which is a constant making air, just an additional addition operation.
So this additional operation would be repeated from zero to array length.
Example, if the right length is one million, it will do this stuff one million times and this if the
right length is 1000, would do this for 1000 times.
So depends on the array length.
This will result in all.
And again, there is another loop making eye from zero array at length and make a product.
So this product is of one.
But all of one.
But this this loop.
This loop would result in all of and because we are making consider a rate at length is an end of an
envelope.
OK.
This is the annotation and this what we mean by an OK, agree that length is and so we are making the
product here, a product operation from zero to array length.
Again, if we have a ray length is one million, it will do the same operation one millionth time and
the product, the operation one millionth time.
So these two loops, these two operations would depend on the length of the array.
So all of and will represent its state.
So no system that out the brain.
And we have seen that when printing anything.
And these are constants.
And some of them are variable defiance.
So of one, look at this of this method, we have oh, one, oh one.
Oh, and oh and oh one.
What are the highest and the highest order of this equation?
If we if we make some motion one.
+1 +, +, +, + +1, we have end to end +3.
We remove the we we have two terms.
We took the highest turn and we remove that constant from this term.
It would result in off.
And so in this case, we are solving every exercise and understanding that time complexity for every
question.
Always, when you have an array, please pay attention for that for that initial value and that limiting
value or the stop condition.
OK.
And the way they increment because in the next video is and the next exercises, we are going to learn
about a new form and using going in deep by making calculations and understanding how the array behavior
and how these conditions, the initial condition, the stop condition and the increment condition,
what works do and affects the time complexity.
So this example, this error, sorry, this method were and this algorithm will behave in time complexity
of of and depending on the array length which is.